I'm going to order the regular schedule to meet my 30 counts for Tuesday January 7, 2025.
But again, put on schedule personal chances.
We have one this Rebecca Jim.
I appreciate the opportunity to visit with you.
There's on the DEQ website.
They have a page so you can actually see permits that are up for a comment.
And there are two that relate to us in the community.
I just wanted to know if you knew about them and if so,
if you would take time to comment when you can.
One is on the BF Goodrich and the mechanism that they're doing the cleanup with.
And they're asking for a permit to continue doing that.
I'm going to please ask you to look through that permit.
It's way over my head.
Please find somebody that can interpret it.
But I believe that it's the process looks to me and to the people that I've been privy to.
They think it's good.
They think it's adequate.
But I would ask you to do is find somebody amongst you to read through it and see if you too agree.
And if so, comment.
But please ask for a public meeting that DEQ and Mitch Lynn and their contractor would provide to the community.
So they would know how these toxins that are lying underneath in their low,
aquifer are being sucked up in how they're being protected by the process.
So I think it's good.
The second one I'm really concerned about and it is a new facility that's been proposed to go in just not too far from here.
I'll describe exactly where.
It's on off-US Highway 69, alternate 69 and South 5592 Road.
It is a project called Argo.
And Argo wants to bring in 164,000 tons of...
Argo.
chicken manure and chicken bedding to turn into a liquid gas.
They would run 24 hours a day and never turn off.
The permit for that facility, I have it here and it's got two pages of abbreviations.
So it's going to take us a while to figure out what it exactly means.
But one of the key terms that you use in here is that they are using a preparatory process.
So they're not going to tell you how they're doing.
In the last time, I'm going to leave these at the door and I have circled this.
Sorry.
Appreciate you.
I'm going to take you to the University of Michigan.
I have a message.
The research method is to say if we want to comment is a city.
That may be the best bet.
That will just the legal response or legal comment to the degree.
Thank you.
Thanks for bringing that to our attention.
Okay.
Three, clean list, clean list.
Mr. Proof.
Psych.
Hi.
I'm Joe's.
Four.
Minutes from the December 2nd and December 16th.
Twenty 24 ringer meetings.
Second.
Super.
Hi.
Chair.
Is that.
Barrett.
Hi.
Five.
Election resolution.
C.C.
Twenty 25.
Dexer.
One calling for proclaiming an ordering.
A nonpartisan general election in the city of Miami.
County of Ottawa.
State of Oklahoma on Tuesday.
April 1st.
Twenty 25.
For the purpose of electing the council members for award one.
North East and war two.
North West.
Have the proposed resolution here for the signature.
If it's approved.
The term.
Or which it.
It covers is nice.
Twenty 25.
Twenty 28.
The election would be April 1st.
Twenty 25.
The filing dates for anyone who chooses to file to run.
And that election would be.
Are you wearing stars or robing us?
Motion to approve.
Council.
Hi.
Students.
I.
Art.
East.
Okay.
Good.
Six.
Easement for.
Twenty it.
30.
Kids.
Ice.
Cleveland.
Brooks.
Button.
Perissa.
Beware.
Reference Boulevard and 30th Avenue Northwest West or Gene Northwest and East of City Airport East Benz
Treps
Council, are you okay?
And so this I got a few representatives from the gas company
John Benz
This is the kind of kind of explaining some of the details of this easement
So initially they came to me
West side I was kind of had questions on the right away slash easement
Thanks sir, be safe my empty surface and location of the pipeline
The pipeline will be asked to the airport fence line
And then typically we cannot put their designation for city Miami within that area between the fence and the airport
So with that being in the case
And somebody comes and challenges us in the future and said, hey, look, the city doesn't have, you know,
it doesn't have any rightfully true in the area.
It's probably because we didn't get anything from the city that would allow us to put the pipeline in the brand.
So what we decided to do was to take the non-exclusive easement for this pipeline, so that we can record this in our accounting.
And be able to prove that we've got the rights from the city, like where we cross your streets and other areas of public health.
Can't prove it's public health fair.
What does the safe, the safe manner by trying to secure the secret from the city?
So, we're with a nation of central.
Is there already a lot of right away there?
That's what we thought.
So that property is that part of the airport?
That's our sector, that's our sector, and it's not.
We can't substantiate that it's actually a public thorough curve, which it is.
We just can't prove that we can use the exercise for you.
Does anybody ever talk to the mind of a tribe?
Well, we don't.
I mean, it's a private property that's city owned.
I mean, if we own it, it's just our private property.
Is there any other utilities over there?
You're talking about the fansrector, where they do their herbicide and stuff like that.
So, you want 15 feet for a 20 inch line.
So, with 15 feet, is that going to restrict us from putting anything else in there?
If it's not exclusive, not exclusive in nature.
So, that means he can't stop somebody else from either crossing or being within that same 15 feet, as long as he takes.
We just can't be.
Is this something we could do a temporary right away?
Just for installation and maintenance and things like that?
The investment that we had, some kind of a temporary type thing.
It almost like license.
And we typically don't do the license because the customer is moving forward to service in the future.
So, the yellow airplane air that the city owns up there, the global war 2 air.
I've been talking to the storage society and local American ice commission about some possible grants to help restore that building.
But, if sounds like we're going to do that for them to give us a grant, it's going to have to be part of the airport property.
which means we probably have to do something there to make it if it didn't already.
I'm not sure.
Would this keep us from making those two work together enough for a grant?
Well, as long as they, as long as they over laugh just with their rights,
and they're not physically going to do anything within that area,
that would prohibit us from operating and being pipeline in the United States.
John, can you explain, or sorry, I mean, could you explain like what this grant bond is doing?
Because I think that was a question.
This is the main figure line.
This is the line.
It starts at our town water in North Wales.
Hopkins and Scepter.
Why we discovered a couple of years ago working on our questions about it?
So you already got an easement there.
Why don't you use that easement?
Because, first of all, in terms of 25, I don't mind.
Four foot.
Scepter.
It's what they saw for foot of the building.
We can't hear it.
I was hoping I'd grow it.
They could.
Scepter.
So the other thing is, it's just, it's going to be next and possible.
could you clarify what runs through the line two because I think adding question about that to
natural gas. So you guys are with O&D that surprised the community. Okay.
So you said the price to go down there, correct.
He's meant you have. He's going to be astronomical. What's astronomical?
Ballpark. Correct me if I'm reading this wrong, but for the he's meant that you're talking
about what you want to give us $10. Well, the $10 is part of this. When I say that we have to have
say $1 in the bag, it's either ration or $10. But yeah, we're doing this to basically upgrade the system
for the city, man. My name is to avoid any total softage of service, intervention of service.
It's very critical to the city as well as hotings and all the other people that are ready.
No. I need a roof on that yellow airplane hangar I was talking about.
But $10 don't cover it, but it's a lot cheaper than $10 million.
The saving money. So we're still saving lots of money.
You know, we're fixing that historical building in the process.
We'll put your name on it.
And it's already yellow.
Yeah.
It's legal in that one.
So where this runs, like from Veterans Boulevard, does the line run, I'm trying to look
at your map here that's overlaid on the satellite view.
Does the gas line run east and west there?
And then you're going to connect the south to North at Veterans.
Right, right.
No, I get that.
But I'm saying the proposed line.
The proposal.
Mm-hmm.
North.
Okay.
And then head on North there.
And then go underneath the tracks.
Yeah.
To set the ones that you stored in a street.
You sent it here.
Countdowns.
There.
Do you have any comments on this at all?
Right there.
There's the other one down there on Newman Road.
Right in front of Tracker.
The one that you're going to be hooking into.
That's the big one.
The big white one.
That's the chamber.
That's around.
That's the town board.
That's.
When we get our gas from the southern side of the south side.
We're going to.
Two years.
One of the skeletons.
You're going to replace that piece of angle across the road.
There.
This line.
They're great.
They're going to be talking about a glass.
Glicks.
The sessions.
We can get here.
Okay.
Would they be talking man?
The skeleton.
The executive session will just be off.
It.
What is this?
So if you have the hang around, I'm not sure that they're going to decide bringing in, but in case we have other questions.
I'll wrap there.
Thank you.
Seven.
Mayor's on nice to the red points.
Nice to the board.
The adjustments.
Turned to expire.
21.
Motion to approve.
Hello.
Hi.
Jones.
I.
Eight.
Mayor's on nice to the red points.
The board of adjustments.
Turned to expire.
24.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Circle.
He set.
Jones.
Parts.
Aye.
Nine.
Mayor's on nice to the red point.
Rick Aldrich's the mom housing board.
Turned to expire.
13.
28.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Circle.
Jones.
Parts.
Aye.
Ten.
Another new business.
I've been to which the redness is posted this agenda.
11.
Staff Report.
12.
Mayor.
Council.
13.
So you may have your communications.
Now you two.
My.
I was going to dismiss.
Mr.
And.
Somebody.
So I'm crystal.
So we're excited.
14.
adjournment.
Motion.
Thank you.
Circle.
Aye.
Jones.
Parts.